Akon Ekpo, Ph.D.

Assistant Professor

Kalamazoo, Michigan Area Marketing and Advertising

Current

- 1. Assistant Professor of Marketing at Western Michigan University
- 1. University of Illinois at Chicago
- **Previous**
- 2. , Allstate Insurance Company
- 3. , Bank One (currently JP Morgan Chase)
- 1. Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Business Administration (Marketing) at University of Illinois at Chicago

Education

259 connections Send a message More options

Contact Info

Summary

Research Summary:

I study the social role of technology consumption in the lives of consumers, particularly, how technology enables marginalized consumers to transcend social inequities. My research is an intersection between consumers, technology and marketplace diversity and inclusion; and addresses the significant need for continued expression and voice of marginalized consumers in marketing discourse. Topic areas include:

- Technology Consumption
- Social Media/Digital Marketing
- Marketplace Diversity & Inclusion
- Consumer Acculturation
- Consumer Culture Theory

Teaching Interests:

- Social Media Marketing
- Consumer Insights
- Digital Marketing

- Market Research
- Marketing Management
- New Product Development/Open Innovation

Specialties

Consumer Behavior, Marketing Management, Social Media Marketing, Internet Marketing

Experience

Assistant Professor of Marketing

Western Michigan University

Educational Institution; 1001-5000 employees; Higher Education industry

2012 – Present (less than a year)

Recommend Akon's work at Western Michigan University

PhD Candidate & Instructor

University of Illinois at Chicago Report this position

Educational Institution; 10,001+ employees; Higher Education industry

2006 – May 2012 (6 years)

Akon has 1 recommendation (1 report) including:

• 2nd John Paul Mallari, Student, University of Illinois at Chicago

Recommend Akon's work at University of Illinois at Chicago

Project Manager

Allstate Insurance Company

Public Company; 10,001+ employees; ALL; Insurance industry

2002 – 2006 (4 years)

Akon has 1 recommendation (1 co-worker) including:

• 1st Christi<u>na Outlay, PhD, PMP</u>, PROGRAM MANAGER / SERVICE MANAGEMENT PROGRAM MANAGEMENT OFFICE. Allstate Insurance

Recommend Akon's work at Allstate Insurance Company

Quality Assurance Analyst

Bank One (currently JP Morgan Chase)

2001 - 2002 (1 year)

Akon has 1 recommendation (1 co-worker) including:

2nd David Griggs, MBA, Vice President, JP Morgan Chase

Recommend Akon's work at Bank One (currently JP Morgan Chase)

Applications Developer

UOP LLC

Public Company; 1001-5000 employees; Oil & Energy industry

2000 - 2001 (1 year)

Recommend Akon's work at UOP LLC

Software Design Engineer

Rand McNally

Privately Held; 201-500 employees; Publishing industry

1998 – 2000 (2 years)

Akon has 2 recommendations (1 manager, 1 co-worker) including:

- 2nd Lisa Ratajczyk, Director, QA & Support, Rand McNally
 2nd Diana Turgeon, Director, Human Resources, Rand McNally & Company

Recommend Akon's work at Rand McNally

Skills & Expertise Endorsements Learn more

1. 2 Consumer Behaviour

Education

University of Illinois at Chicago

Doctor of Philosophy (Ph.D.), Business Administration (Marketing)

2006 - 2012

Activities and Societies: PhD Project Marketing Doctoral Student Association

Recommend Akon's work at University of Illinois at Chicago

DePaul University

Bachelor of Science, Information Systems

1996 - 2000

Activities and Societies: CTI Dean's List, National Dean's List, Who's Who of American University Students, Project STAR Mentor, Computer Science Society, Sigma Gamma Rho, INROADS/Chicago

Recommend Akon's work at DePaul University

Whitney M. Young Magnet H.S.

Recommend Akon's work at Whitney M. Young Magnet H.S.